<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🧠 A Bipolar Brain</title>
    <link>https://spoonietunes.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 🧠 A Bipolar Brain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://spoonietunes.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Having a difficult time</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/nov-hypo/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/nov-hypo/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/nov-hypo/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content warning: self-harm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the midst of a hypomanic episode. A few days ago was closest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been to checking myself into the psych ward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a couple months I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pretty elevated mood - I&amp;rsquo;ve been going very fast, moving fast, speaking quickly, tons of ideas, high anxiety, high irritability. I call this &amp;ldquo;turbo.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to happen every Spring and Fall. This Spring it was bad enough that I went on a new medicine, seroquel. Recently it got so intense I had some self-harm thoughts. I&amp;rsquo;ve sort of had them before, but this time seemed different&amp;hellip; I was really considering them as a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thinking was &amp;ldquo;my brain is going so fast, I&amp;rsquo;m so irritable and anxious&amp;hellip; maybe if I hurt myself just a little I&amp;rsquo;d have a distraction, with the added bonus that I&amp;rsquo;d have some outward sign of distress, instead of my invisible mental illness.&amp;rdquo; If I hurt myself enough maybe I could even go to the hospital where I&amp;rsquo;d get to relax, everybody would take care of me, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to work on any of my hundreds of projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a very weird feeling to simultaneously hold two conflicting thoughts; that I should hurt myself and also that I definitely should not hurt myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did instead of following through with these plans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told my wife&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got in touch with my therapist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called in sick to work (I was absolutely in no condition to do any work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately cut back on my coffee consumption (I usually have a single cup of very strong black coffee)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week before it got really bad, my psychiatrist upped my dosage of lamictal (mood stabilizer). I don&amp;rsquo;t have a huge amount of trust in this guy, but I needed to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to handle this intense episode. There was some confusion about how much medicine I was actually supposed to be taking. As you can imagine, this added stress did me no favors. After a lot of back and forth with my doc, his staff, and the pharmacy, I finally got the dosage I should be taking, and started titrating up (increasing my dose  by small amounts until I reach my new dosage).
gg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most effective things I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing to manage this episode have been:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing nothing&lt;/strong&gt;. This is sooooo hard for me. I always have about 10 different projects, and I think these both propel me deeper into hypomania and distract me from my growing anxiety. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a handful of days trying my best to do nothing; just watch tv or doodle. I&amp;rsquo;ve been binging Maria Bamford shows and specials. She&amp;rsquo;s a comedian with bipolar 2 (which is what I have) and her comedy features her illness heavily. It&amp;rsquo;s comforting and validating to hear about her experiences and struggles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking plenty of naps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of guided meditations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hot baths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, it&amp;rsquo;s still a struggle every minute of the day. If I&amp;rsquo;m not super vigilant and paying close attention to my mood and thoughts, I quickly find myself working on a project&amp;hellip; like this post. I really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be writing this at all - I should be doing nothing. But here I am!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my main symptoms of hypomania is oversharing. Pretty meta, I&amp;rsquo;m oversharing about my oversharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s all for now, time to try and do nothing again.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/nov-hypo/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Guiding the firehose</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/guiding_the_firehose/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:02:16 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/guiding_the_firehose/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/guiding_the_firehose/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trigger warning: hypomania&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the toughest things for me when it comes to hypomania is resisting the urge to &lt;em&gt;lean into it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many bipolar folks can attest, hypomania (perhaps even mania) feels good. Well, it feels good until it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Personally, my hypomania is usually filled with euphoria, extreme productivity (the results are sometimes of dubious quality, however), and a drive to do things. When I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing a low-grade hypomanic episode like I am now, it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to try and take advantage of it. I have plenty of skills - thank you, therapy! - that help me tame it and stay calm&amp;hellip; but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get myself to use them. Again: hypomania can feel &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the last few episodes is, at least for a while, &lt;em&gt;guiding the firehose&lt;/em&gt;. I often think of my hypomanic brain as firehose that somebody turned on and ran away; it&amp;rsquo;s uncontrollably shooting out very high-pressure water, writhing around like a caffeinated snake. My brain shoots out a new idea every minute, sometimes more frequently, and I am quickly bombarded. I get started on a project only to have a new, &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; idea. I discard the old project and start the new one&amp;hellip; and the cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I try to &lt;em&gt;guide the firehose.&lt;/em&gt; I try to take advantage of my hypomania and use it &amp;ldquo;for good.&amp;rdquo; Sure, I start some new projects (like this blog) and perhaps learn a new skill or get a new hobby, but I also try to get a grip on the firehose and point it toward more useful things like cleaning or drastically increasing my productivity at work. Just like trying to wrangle a real-life wild firehose, this can be difficult&amp;hellip; But it can also be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some ways I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to conciously focus my hypomania:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of immediately following each new idea, just write it (or type it) down. I have a huge list of &amp;ldquo;ideas&amp;rdquo; that I can turn to once the fountain of ideas has slowed. This also helps me focus, as I&amp;rsquo;m no longer worried about losing my &amp;ldquo;best idea ever.&amp;rdquo; As an added benefit, revisiting these ideas later under less hypomanic circumstances helps me gain some perspective. Not all of my &amp;ldquo;best ideas&amp;rdquo; hold up to the light of day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also apply this &amp;ldquo;write it down&amp;rdquo; mentality to tasks; sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll have a string of ideas like &amp;ldquo;oh! I totally need to send in those receipts,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;ohhh! I think I&amp;rsquo;m due for a dental checkup.&amp;rdquo; If I write these things down, it will be easier to accomplish them once my hypomania fades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I harness my energy to clean. Normally I think cleaning is the worst, but when my brain is going a mile a minute, cleaning has three main benefits: it gives me something to focus on, gives me something physical to help burn off some of my energy, and of course it accomplishes a task that would otherwise be much more difficult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m learning a new technique/skill/hobby, I make an effort to write everything down, so if I decide to, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to pick the hobby up after my episode is over. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that if I don&amp;rsquo;t write things down, returning to the technique/skill/hobby later can be very confusing, and I often forget much of what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few things I&amp;rsquo;ve found to work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an endorsement for letting hypomania go unchecked. Embracing hypomania isn&amp;rsquo;t always a good idea! Inevitably, if I don&amp;rsquo;t slow the course of the episode, I become super anxious, super irritable, and overwhelmed with ideas and projects. If the episode isn&amp;rsquo;t managed at all I end up going completely off the rails, forgetting to eat, ignoring daily tasks, and succumbing to my own world of a million thoughts a minute. With my current cocktail of meds, my hypomania doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually get so intense, and I feel comfortable sometimes harnessing it &amp;ldquo;for good.&amp;rdquo; If I notice my anxiety and irritability rising too much, I&amp;rsquo;ll pump the breaks and use my coping skills.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/guiding_the_firehose/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Wrangling my racing thoughts</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/sep20-2021/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 16:19:16 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/sep20-2021/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/sep20-2021/ -&lt;p&gt;Today was like many days I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past. I wake up, get an idea in my head, and spend the majority of the day working on that one idea. Sometimes that idea splinters into a constellation of other ideas. Sometimes when the constellation gets too large, the nodes too numerous, my anxiety kicks in to high gear. &lt;em&gt;How am I going to accomplish all of these things before I have to go to sleep tonight?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, after a few years of therapy and lots of practice, these days aren&amp;rsquo;t quite the same as they used to be. Yes, I spent the majority of my day working on a project (this blog!), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t go completely down the rabbit hole. I ate lunch, I attended to my job (and actually accomplished everything I set out to do), and even did some chores. Meanwhile, my brain was shouting &amp;ldquo;No, do this! Or this! Or wait I have another idea! Stop that, we need to do this thing I just thought of&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always difficult, but for whatever reason today has been slightly easier. For that I&amp;rsquo;m thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/sep20-2021/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Welcome back, hypomania</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/welcome_back_hypomania/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 12:38:33 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/welcome_back_hypomania/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/welcome_back_hypomania/ -&lt;p&gt;Back in 2019, shortly after my Bipolar II diagnosis, &lt;a href=&#34;https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here&#34;&gt;I started an anonymous blog&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;em&gt;This blog is a reboot of that blog.&lt;/em&gt;) Naturally it was my hypomania that gave me the idea and motivated me to do it. If you are bipolar as well, the pressure (the &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;ridiculously strong urge&lt;/em&gt;) to create might be something you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I created the blog and just as quickly deserted it. Again, if you&amp;rsquo;re bipolar, you know how that goes. Start a project while hypomanic/manic, good luck finishing it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to experience my biggest periods of hypomania in the Spring and Fall. Just like clockwork, as the leaves started to change and the air started to cool, my energy level shot up. Racing thoughts - tons of ideas - tons of energy&amp;hellip; If it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the skills I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in therapy I would almost certainly be completely off the rails right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, luckily, I have some tools to try and keep things under control. Breathing exercises, hot baths, avoiding too much coffee and alcohol, checking in with myself frequently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, here I am, starting another new blog! I have that almost-uncontrollable urge to share. The whole &amp;ldquo;oversharing&amp;rdquo; thing, as I understand it, is a common bipolar thing. I&amp;rsquo;m convincing myself that this could be a nice outlet for all my ideas and energy, and perhaps it might also help others. It&amp;rsquo;s been two and a half years since my diagnosis (and starting therapy) and I have come a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that whatever I write here during this hypomanic episode will be helpful, either to me, you, or both!&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/welcome_back_hypomania/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>How did I get here? (Part 2)</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here_part2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 15:09:06 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here_part2/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here_part2/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here/&#34;&gt;my last post &lt;/a&gt;I described a bit of my history and events leading up to my search for a therapist. In this post, I’ll share how I came to find a therapist and what happened next. Note: This was originally posted in June 2019, about 15 days after my bipolar diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;searching-for-a-therapist&#34;&gt;Searching for a therapist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought finding a therapist would be easy. I logged into my insurance website, clicked about 24 buttons and links, and was faced with a list of 300-some mental health providers in my geographic area and in my network. That’s a lot! I used even more buttons and links to narrow down the search to male providers, providers who list “depression” and “anger issues” as things they treat. That lowered it down to 100 or so. After even more fine-tuning, I finally managed to generate a more reasonable list of 40 providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://psychologytoday.com/us/therapists&#34;&gt;the Psychology Today “find a therapist” page &lt;/a&gt; for each of the 40 providers. I immediately ruled out any that mentioned religion (in my mind that is a completely irrelevant piece of information to mention, it seems exclusionary to people of other wordviews, and I also happen to be an agnostic atheist). I also ruled out anybody who went to school at private religious institutions I know to have questionable curriculums. This lowered my list down to 10 or 15 therapists. Ok, now we’re getting somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One therapist caught my eye: he mentioned “evidence-based,” “mindfulness,” “CBT,” and a few other keywords that sparked my interest. He looked like he was about the same age as me, wasn’t too far away, and according to Pyschology Today he was accepting patients. I found his website and signed up for a free 15 minute consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty sure this was an in-person meeting, but I wasn’t 100% sure. I thought about calling the office to confirm, but due to my periodic phone anxiety I didn’t. When I showed up at the office for the appointment, the person at the desk said the therapist wasn’t there… and they also said the consultations are usually over the phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I sat in the parking lot, in my car, and talked to the therapist over the phone. He apologized profusely for the confusion. I described my symptoms; my high periods and low periods, anger issues, agitation, and history. He said that I should see somebody soon, but that he wasn’t actually taking new patients. He put me on his waiting list and gave me the names of therapists that were actually taking new patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through that list, once again weeding out people that mention religion or attended biased religious schools. I was left with a few people that weren’t in my insurance network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to square one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;continuing-the-search&#34;&gt;Continuing the search&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I’d been searching for a therapist for two weeks. The anxiety of the search was added to my already-existing anxiety. It seemed ironic that in an effort to get help with anxiety I needed to go through more anxiety first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, back to the original list of providers, I found some that might be a good fit for me. I got as far as scheduling an appointment with one when I heard back from another: he described his approach and then (in not so many words) suggested that he and I might not be a good fit. I suspected his was a religious angle even though he didn’t mention that in his profile. However, he suggested somebody that would be a good fit for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d skipped over this therapist before because the Psychology Today list said he was out of my network. His profile was great, otherwise; he mentioned “evidence-based,” “mindfulness,” he had cool glasses, and appeared to be about the same age as me. He also listed some things that resonated with me, such as “LGBT ally,” “vegan ally,” and I think even “social justice” ally. I’m not LGBT or vegan (yet) but I totally support all those things. Perhaps we would be a great fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a last-ditch effort, I emailed him and asked about my insurance provider. He replied almost immediately, saying that the practice he worked with was in the process of accepting my insurance, and that he was in fact accepting patients! The tone of his email (and the lack of grammatical errors and typos compared to some other therapists I emailed) was more evidence that we would connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whoohoo! At last!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;appointment-scheduled&#34;&gt;Appointment scheduled!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some communication with the practice manager, I was all set up and ready to schedule an appointment. I’m not sure what the PM had to do to speed up the insurance approval, but I suspect there was a lot that the folks at the practice did to make this happen for me… and for that I am grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first therapy session was scheduled. I was excited to get some help, nervous about what he’d say, and worried that I’d ramble too much and obscure the important stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could he help me tame my depression? Could he tell me why I had periods of high energy and productivity followed by low periods? Would I go on new medicine? What would the “therapy homework” be like, and how hard would it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was I ready for therapy?&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here_part2/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>How did I get here?</title>
        <link>https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 15:03:14 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here/</guid>
        <description>🧠 A Bipolar Brain https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was originally posted in June 2019, about 15 days after my bipolar diagnosis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trigger warning: Depression&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many bipolar individuals (or individuals living with bipolar disorder) I was misdiagnosed with clinical depression and anxiety at first. This is apparently very common, with a correct diagnosis of bipolar disorder on average taking a staggering 10 years! After my first diagnosis, my doctor put me on Zoloft. At first, things got a lot better. My frequent low moods, sometimes-crippling anxiety, and bouts of anger, subsided. I felt more like myself, happier, and able to do more in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while, however, the medicine didn’t seem to work as well. As Autumn approached, the low moods, anxiety, and anger returned. Maybe it was seasonal affective disorder? At my request, my doc upped my dosage of Zoloft. Again, it seemed to help for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;going-fast&#34;&gt;Going fast!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come Spring I began to feel even better. I was, more or less, back to my old self! I was filled with a million ideas. I started new hobbies on a weekly basis. I was laser-focused in my obsession with a wide variety of interests. This is the way I’d always been; this was the “normal” me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, as it had sometimes before, my energy, enthusiasm, and obsession with these projects went up a notch. I became agitated, even more driven, and supremely focused on my projects. I had to work on them. There wasn’t enough time to focus on them. I’d spend all day jumping from one to the next, barely eating, barely stopping to rest, and the result was a prolific output of creations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned embroidery, then I learned how to use a sewing machine. I sewed an apron, a messenger bag, a pen/paintbrush roll, a belt, a foraging bag. I took up watercolors and painted 5-10 paintings per day. I started experimenting with collage. I bought a ton of art supplies. I converted a room of our house into an art studio. I strung string from the walls to hang my creations. I got into bookmaking and started making notebooks. Homemade hardcovers and softcovers began to stack up throughout the house. I bought four different kinds of paper. I decided to get into bullet journaling, and instead of buying a premade notebook, I made one from scratch. I made stamps out of wood and pink erasers. I made a sketchbook and filled it with a never-ending stream of visual ideas: stamps, paint, drawings, crayons, shapes, landscapes, abstracts, dots, all created with furious speed in a very short time. I got into weaving and made a variety of small woven items. I decided I needed to try making my own paper, so I spent days researching everything I could. I spent the better part of a day making ten sheets of recycled paper out of old paper in the kitchen. I used 2 buckets and our (food) blender and got little bits of gooey paper everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the midst of this intense period, I knew I was going a little fast, but it was more amusing than alarming. At one point I decided to make a “mind map” of my recent obsessions to show how I jumped from one idea to another. To me it made (and makes) perfect sense, although I have to admit it looks like the scrawling of a crazy* person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://spoonietunes.org/mindmap.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mind map&#34; title=&#34;mind map&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started with hiking patches and my desire to make them myself
The number of different things I’d been doing was comical, and the humor was not lost on me. I was also driven to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My family was impressed by my output; they were proud of me. They enjoyed my drive to learn new things, and aside from the messes I made, thought it was great. Of course they didn’t know how anxious and agitated I got. They didn’t know I was barely eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of this “high” period was also irritation and anger if anything interfered with my work on these projects. Again, I had to do them. Along with a million ideas for new projects and hobbies, I was also filled with confidence; I was creating amazing things. I needed to keep making them so the world could enjoy them. It would be a disservice to humankind if I stopped creating! I owed it to the world to increase my already-prolific creative output. Plus, it felt good. Really good. I was on top of the world. I had so much energy, and I was putting it to good use by creating things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;going-slow&#34;&gt;Going slow&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then something happened, just as it had in the past. One day I woke up and my drive was gone. My energy, enthusiasm, and will to create was gone. My will to do anything was gone. My happiness was gone. I could barely get out of bed. I wanted to sleep all the time, and sometimes I did sleep all the time. I shirked responsibilities. I thought about all my projects and wondered why I had been so interested in them; now, nothing interested me. Spending all that time seemed silly and pointless to me. The world was boring and I was numb. Everything seemed incredibly difficult. I was incredibly hungry and ate large quantities of whatever I could easily find, whatever would fill my belly. Then I’d go back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the depression that I’d experienced before, and with increasing frequency during the last few years. This was why my doctor diagnosed me with depression. In talking with him, I didn’t think to share my periods of intense creativity, drive, and energy. In my brain, that was the real me, that was my baseline, and the depression was the only thing that needed fixing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this particularly intense period and its abrupt shift to depression, I realized I needed help. Zoloft was not doing the trick. I needed to find out what was really going on with me. That’s when I started looking for a therapist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read what happened next in &lt;a href=&#34;https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here_part2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I’m not sure how I feel about the word “crazy.” Part of me thinks it is offensive to those living with mental illness, like me. Another part of me wants to take ownership of the word just like LGBTQ+ folks took back “queer.” Yet another part of me wants to avoid labels entirely; I am not my diagnosis.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://spoonietunes.org/post/how_did_i_get_here/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 